<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<LocalizedText>
		
		
	
		
	
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Kulturkampf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>[ICON_DISTRICT_ENCAMPMENT] Encampment district buildings provide [ICON_Culture] Culture equivalent to their [ICON_Production] Production output. +10% [ICON_Culture] culture for cities with garrison units. Build the Ruhr Valley +50% faster.</Text>
		</Row>


		


		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Otto von Bismarck</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Hail mighty Bismarck, first chancellor of Germany and her empire! Germany is an upstart nation, fashioned from the ruins of the Holy Roman Empire and finally unified in 1871, a little more than a century ago. The German people have proven themselves to be creative, industrious and ferocious warriors. Despite enduring great catastrophe in the first half of the 20th century, Germany remains a worldwide economic, artistic and technological leader. Great Prince Bismarck, the German people look to you to lead them to greater days of glory. Their determination is strong and they turn to you, their beloved iron chancellor, to guide them once more. Will you rule and conquer through blood and iron, or foster the Germanic arts and industry? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Civilopedia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_TITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Otto von Bismarck</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_SUBTITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Chancellor of the German Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_QUOTE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Diplomacy without arms is music without instruments.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Otto von Bismarck, Duke of Lauenburg and Prince of Bismarck, born in Schönhausen on April 1, 1815 and died on July 30, 1898 in Friedrichsruh, is a Prussian then German statesman. He was at the same time Minister-President of the Kingdom of Prussia from 1862 to 1890, Chancellor of the Confederation of Northern Germany from 1867 to 1871, before becoming Chancellor of the New German Empire in 1871, a post he occupied until 1890, while retaining his position as minister-president of Prussia. He plays a decisive role in German unification. At the beginning of his political career, Bismarck made a name for himself by defending the interests of the junkers, a Prussian nobility, of which he is a part, from the conservative benches. He was appointed minister-president of Prussia in 1862. In the Prussian constitutional conflict, he fought against the liberals to maintain the primacy of the monarchy. Also Minister of Foreign Affairs, he launched the Duchies war and the Austro-Prussian war between 1864 and 1866, and thereby imposes the supremacy of Prussia in Germany. The Franco-Prussian war of 1870 solves the German question by retaining the German solution, defended by Prussia, and leads to German unification in 1871. Then, in terms of foreign policy, he tries to establish a balance between the great European powers thanks to a system of alliances.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In domestic politics, beginning in 1866, Bismarck first joined the moderate liberals, which led to the vote of many reforms such as the institution of civil marriage, which meets the resistance of Catholics, which he strongly opposes in instituting Kulturkampf policy. In the late 1870s, he broke away from the Liberals and returned to the Conservatives. During this phase, the laws for protectionism and state interventionism are passed. A social security system is also created. The 1880s are mostly marked by anti-socialist laws. In 1890, Bismarck's differences of opinion with the new Emperor William II led to his departure. After his resignation, Bismarck continues to play a political role, criticizing the action of his successor. He also writes his memoirs, which strongly influence the image of German public opinion. Until the middle of the twentieth century, German historians have largely judged its action in a positive way, the latter being, in this nationalist period, associated with the unification of Germany. However, after the Second World War, critics increased: he was accused of being responsible, as the founder of the German Empire, for the failure of democracy in Germany. More modern approaches to history, however, attempt to put Bismarck's action, with its strengths and shortcomings, in the context of its time with the political structure that was then in place.</Text>
		</Row>



 
		
		
		
		
		<!--Diplomacy-->
		<!--FIRST MEET-->
		<!--First AI line-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Im Namen des großen deutschen Volkes heiße ich Euch willkommen! (In the name of the great German people, I bid you welcome!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to visit nearby City-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Hallo, ich bin Otto von Bismarck, Kanzler von Deutschland! Möchten Sie unsere nächste Stadt besuchen? (Hello, I am Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor of Germany! Would you like to visit our nearest city?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI accepts Human invitation-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Danke.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to exchange Capital Information-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich lade Sie ein, Informationen über unsere jeweiligen Hauptstädte auszutauschen. (I invite you to exchange information on our respective capitals.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--GREETINGS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Gruss!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DELEGATION-->
		<!--AI Accepts-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich akzeptiere deine Delegation mit Freude! (I accept your delegation with joy.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Nein, leider. (Unfortunately, no.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich sende Ihnen eine Wirtschaftsdelegation mit Geschenken aus meinem Land: Würstchen und Bier, viel Bier ...(I send you a business delegation with gifts from my country: sausages and beer, lots of beer ...)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--OPEN BORDERS-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ja, ich bin damit einverstanden, meine Grenzen für Ihre kleinen Soldaten zu öffnen. (Yes I agree to open my borders to your little soldiers.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI rejects from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Wir sind im Moment nicht interessiert. (We are not interested at the moment.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Sind Sie damit einverstanden, dass wir Ihr Territorium durchqueren? (Will you allow our units to cross through your territory?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE FRIENDSHIP-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich stimme zu, unsere Freundschaft der Welt zu erklären. (I accept your offer of friendship.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects from human -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich weigere mich, der Welt unsere Freundschaft zu erklären. (I refuse such a ridiculous offer.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests friendship from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Es wäre in Eurem Interesse, dass Ihr dieses Angebot sorgfältig prüft. (It would be in your best interest, to carefully consider this proposal of friendship.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human accepts AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich danke dir. (Thank you, friend.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human rejects AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Da ist das bedauerlich. (How disappointing.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ALLIANCE-->
		<!--AI Requests an alliance from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Möchten Sie eine Allianz bilden? (Would you like to form an alliance?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--KUDOS & WARNINGS-->
		<!--AI Kudos-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Du bist zäh! (you are tenacious)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Warnings-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Du bist ein Weichei! (You are a wimp!).</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI warns player for border troops-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ein übelster Haufen von Soldaten, die sich in der Nähe unserer Grenzen gebildet haben ... Willst du sie entfernen, bevor ein unglücklicher Vorfall eintritt? (A nauseabond pile of soldiers formed near our borders ... do you want to remove them before an unfortunate incident occurs?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--TRADE-->
		<!--AI Accepts Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DENOUNCE-->
		<!--From Human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich prangere dich öffentlich an! (I publicly denounce you.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--From AI-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Sie planen in unseren Rücken. Sei versichert, dass ich andere warnen werde! (You are plotting in our backs. Rest assured that I will warn others!) (Denounces You).</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE WAR-->
		<!--Human Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich kann nicht warten bis Ihr noch mächtiger geworden seid. Bereitet Euch also auf den Krieg vor! (I cannot wait until ye grow even mightier. Therefore, prepare for war!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Verderbter Bösewicht! Wir werden Euch unter die Erde bringen! (Corrupted villain! We will bring you into the ground!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MAKE PEACE-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Lass uns Frieden machen! (Let's make peace!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI refuses human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Natürlich nein. (Naturally no.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Ich schlage einen Waffenstillstand vor, wann denkst du? (I propose a truce, when do you think?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DEFEAT-->
		<!--AI is Defeated-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Deutschland ist zerstört worden. Ich weine um die zukünftigen Generationen. (Germany has been destroyed. I weep for the future generations.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is Defeated (will see this in hotseat)-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>[LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY]</Text>
		</Row>

		


		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GEDEMO_BISMARK_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Iron Chancellor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GEDEMO_BISMARK_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Never gives up items in a peace deal, and likes civilizations who match that approach. Dislikes civlizations who have capitulated or who have never gone to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_REASON_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have fought honorably and not capitulated in a peace deal.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_REASON_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have never gone to war or have capitulated in a peace deal.)</Text>
		</Row>



		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_OR_ON_IT" Language="de_DE">
			<Text>Der Anführer möchte sehen, wie Ihr kämpft, sonst weiß sie, dass Ihr für Frieden zahlt</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_NEVER_WARRED" Language="de_DE">
			<Text>Der Anführer möchte Euch kämpfen sehen.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_PAID_FOR_PEACE" Language="de_DE">
			<Text>Der Anführer weiß, dass Ihr für den Frieden bezahlt habt.</Text>
		</Replace>

		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_OR_ON_IT"	Language="en_US">
			<Text>The Leader wants to see you fight or knows you paid for peace.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_NEVER_WARRED" Language="en_US">
			<Text>The Leader wants to see you fight.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_PAID_FOR_PEACE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>The Leader knows you paid for peace.</Text>
		</Replace>
		

		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_OR_ON_IT" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Le Dirigeant veut vous voir combattre, ou sait que vous avez acheté la paix.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_NEVER_WARRED" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Le Dirigeant veut vous voir combattre.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_WITH_SHIELD_PAID_FOR_PEACE" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Le Dirigeant sait que vous avez acheté la paix.</Text>
		</Replace>
		
		
		
		
		
		
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GEDEMO_BISMARK_NAME" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Chancelier de Fer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_GEDEMO_BISMARK_DESCRIPTION" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ne lache rien dans les négociations de paix, et apprécie les ivilizations avec la même approche. N'apprécie pas les civilisations qui ont capitulé ou qui n'ont jamais fait la guerre.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_REASON_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>(Vous avez combattu avec honneur et n'avez pas capitulé dans un traité de paix.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_REASON_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>(Vous n'avez jamais fait la guerre ou avez capitulé dans un traité de paix.)</Text>
		</Row>


		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_NAME"  Language="fr_FR" >
			<Text>Kulturkampf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_DESCRIPTION"  Language="fr_FR" >
			<Text>Les Batiments du district [ICON_DISTRICT_ENCAMPMENT] Campement fournissent l'équivalent de leur [ICON_Production] Production générée en [ICON_Culture] Culture. +10% culture [ICON_Culture] pour les villes avec des unités en garnison. Construisez la Vallée de la Ruhr 50% plus vite.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		

		
		
		
		
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Otto von Bismarck</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Salutations puissant Bismarck, premier chancelier de l'empire allemand! L'Allemagne est une nation par excellence, façonnée à partir des ruines du Saint Empire romain germanique et finalement unifiée en 1871, il y a un peu plus d'un siècle. Les Allemands se sont révélés être des guerriers créatifs, industrieux et féroces. Malgré une grande catastrophe dans la première moitié du 20ème siècle, l'Allemagne reste un leader économique, artistique et technologique mondial. Grand prince Bismarck, les Allemands se tournent vers vous pour les conduire à de plus grands jours de gloire. Leur détermination est forte et ils se tournent vers vous, leur chancelier de fer bien-aimé, pour les guider une fois de plus. Allez-vous gouverner et vaincre par le sang et le fer, ou encourager les arts et l'industrie germaniques? Pouvez-vous construire une civilisation qui résistera à l'épreuve du temps?
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Civilopedia french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_TITLE" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Otto von Bismarck</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_SUBTITLE" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Chancelier Imperial d'Allemagne</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_QUOTE" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>La diplomatie sans les armes, c'est la musique sans les instruments.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Otto von Bismarck, duc de Lauenburg et prince de Bismarck, né à Schönhausen le 1er avril 1815 et mort le 30 juillet 1898 à Friedrichsruh, est un homme d'État prussien puis allemand. Il est à la fois ministre-président du royaume de Prusse de 1862 à 1890, chancelier de la confédération de l'Allemagne du Nord de 1867 à 1871, avant d'accéder au poste de premier chancelier du nouvel Empire allemand en 1871, poste qu'il occupe jusqu'en 1890, tout en conservant sa place de ministre-président de Prusse. Il joue un rôle déterminant dans l'unification allemande. Au début de sa carrière politique, Bismarck se fait un nom en défendant les intérêts des junkers, petite noblesse prussienne, dont il fait partie, depuis les bancs conservateurs. Il est nommé ministre-président de Prusse en 1862. Dans le conflit constitutionnel prussien, il lutte contre les libéraux pour maintenir la primauté de la monarchie. Également ministre des Affaires étrangères, il déclenche la guerre des Duchés puis la guerre austro-prussienne entre 1864 et 1866, et impose par là-même la suprématie de la Prusse en Allemagne. La guerre franco-prussienne de 1870 permet de résoudre la question allemande en retenant la solution petite-allemande, défendue par la Prusse, et entraîne l'unification allemande en 1871. Ensuite, sur le plan de la politique extérieure, il essaie d'établir un équilibre entre les grandes puissances européennes grâce à un système d'alliances.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>En politique intérieure, à partir de 1866, Bismarck s'allie d'abord aux libéraux modérés, ce qui conduit au vote de nombreuses réformes comme l'institution du mariage civil, qui rencontre la résistance des catholiques, auxquels il s'oppose durement en instituant la politique du Kulturkampf. À la fin des années 1870, il se sépare des libéraux, pour renouer avec les conservateurs. Durant cette phase, sont votées les lois pour le protectionnisme et l'interventionnisme étatique. Un système de sécurité sociale est également créé. Les années 1880 sont surtout marquées par les lois antisocialistes. En 1890, les divergences de point de vue de Bismarck avec le nouvel empereur Guillaume II conduisent à son départ. Après sa démission, Bismarck continue de jouer un rôle politique, en critiquant l'action de son successeur. Il écrit également ses mémoires, qui influencent fortement l'image que se forge de lui l'opinion publique allemande. Jusqu'au milieu du XXe siècle, les historiens allemands jugent en grande majorité son action de manière positive, celle-ci étant, dans cette période nationaliste, associée à l'unification de l'Allemagne. Cependant, après la Seconde Guerre mondiale, les critiques s'accentuent : il est alors accusé d'être responsable, en tant que fondateur de l'Empire allemand, de l'échec de la démocratie en Allemagne. Des approches plus modernes de l'histoire tentent cependant de remettre l'action de Bismarck, avec ses forces et ses manques, dans le contexte de son époque avec la structure politique qui était alors en place.</Text>
		</Row>



		
		
		
		<!--Diplomacy french-->
		<!--FIRST MEET french-->
		<!--First AI line french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Im Namen des großen deutschen Volkes heiße ich Euch willkommen! (Je vous souhaite la bienvenue au nom du grand Peuple Allemand!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to visit nearby City french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Hallo, ich bin Otto von Bismarck, Reichskanzler! Möchten Sie unsere nächste Stadt besuchen? (Bienvenue en Allemagne, étranger! Avez-vous déjà visité la Grande Prusse?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI accepts Human invitation french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Danke.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to exchange Capital Information french -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich lade Sie ein, Informationen über unsere jeweiligen Hauptstädte auszutauschen. (je vous invite à échanger des informations sur nos capitales respectives.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--GREETINGS french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Gruss!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DELEGATION french-->
		<!--AI Accepts french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich akzeptiere deine Delegation mit Freude! (I accept your delegation with joy.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Nein, leider. (Non, malheureusement.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich sende Ihnen eine Wirtschaftsdelegation mit Geschenken aus meinem Land: Würstchen und Bier, viel Bier ... (Je vous envoie une délégation commerciale avec des cadeaux de mon pays : des saucisses et de la bière, beaucoup de bière...)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--OPEN BORDERS french-->
		<!--AI accepts from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ja, ich bin damit einverstanden, meine Grenzen für Ihre kleinen Soldaten zu öffnen. (C'est avec plaisir que nous ouvrons nos frontières à vos petits soldats.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI rejects from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Wir sind im Moment nicht interessiert. (Nous ne sommes pas intéressés pour l'instant.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Sind Sie damit einverstanden, dass wir Ihr Territorium durchqueren? (Permettrez-vous à nos unités de traverser votre territoire?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE FRIENDSHIP french-->
		<!--AI accepts from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich stimme zu, unsere Freundschaft der Welt zu erklären. (J'accepte de declarer notre amitié.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich weigere mich, der Welt unsere Freundschaft zu erklären. (Je n'ai pas envie d'afficher mon amitié pour vous pour le moment.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests friendship from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Es wäre in Eurem Interesse, dass Ihr dieses Angebot sorgfältig prüft. (Cela serait dans votre meilleur interet que d'accepter cette proposition d'amitié.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human accepts AI requests, AI responds french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich danke dir. (Je vous remercie.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human rejects AI requests, AI responds french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Da ist das bedauerlich. (C'est fâcheux.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ALLIANCE-->
		<!--AI Requests an alliance from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Möchten Sie eine Allianz bilden? (Aimeriez-vous former une alliance?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--KUDOS & WARNINGS french-->
		<!--AI Kudos-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Du bist zäh Ah! Ah! (Vous êtes tenace, j'aime ça!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Warnings french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Du bist ein Weichei! (Vous êtes une mauviette!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI warns player for border troops french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ein übelster Haufen von Soldaten, die sich in der Nähe unserer Grenzen gebildet haben ... Willst du sie entfernen, bevor ein unglücklicher Vorfall eintritt? (un amas nauseabond de soldats s'est formé prés de nos frontières...voulez-vous bien les retirer avant qu'un incident facheux se produise?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--TRADE french-->
		<!--AI Accepts Deal french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects Deal french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DENOUNCE french-->
		<!--From Human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich prangere dich öffentlich an! (Je vous denonce publiquement.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--From AI french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Sie planen in unseren Rücken. Sei versichert, dass ich andere warnen werde! (Vous complotez dans notre dos. Soyez assuré que je vais prevenir les autres!) (Dénonciation)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE WAR french-->
		<!--Human Declares War french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich kann nicht warten bis Ihr noch mächtiger geworden seid. Bereitet Euch also auf den Krieg vor! (Je ne peux pas attendre d'avantage que vous deveniez plus fort...ainsi préparez-vous pour la guerre!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declares War french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Verderbter Bösewicht! Wir werden Euch unter die Erde bringen! (Souillure corrompue! Nous allons vous battre à plat de couture!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MAKE PEACE french-->
		<!--AI accepts from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Lass uns Frieden machen! (Faisons la paix!)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI refuses human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Natürlich nein. (Naturellement non.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Ich schlage einen Waffenstillstand vor, wann denkst du? (Je vous propose une trève, quand pensez-vous?)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DEFEAT french-->
		<!--AI is Defeated french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>Deutschland ist zerstört worden. Ich weine um die zukünftigen Generationen. (L'Allemagne a été détruite. Je pleure pour les générations futures.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is Defeated (will see this in hotseat) french-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="fr_FR">
			<Text>[LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY]</Text>
		</Row>

		

	
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_NAME" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>文化斗争</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_DESCRIPTION" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>解锁科技铸铜术后，立即解锁商业中心。[newline]军营区域从商业中心获得标准 [ICON_Culture] 文化值相邻加成，从商业同业公会获得大量 [Icon_Production] 生产力相邻加成。</Text>
		</Row>


		


		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>奥托·冯·俾斯麦</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>万岁，强大的俾斯麦，德意志帝国第一任宰相！德国是一个新兴国家，建立在神圣罗马帝国的废墟之上，最终于一个多世纪前的1871年统一。德意志人民已证明自己是富有创造力、勤劳且凶猛的战士。尽管在20世纪上半叶遭受了巨大灾难，德国仍然是全球经济、艺术和技术的领导者。伟大的俾斯麦亲王，德意志人民期待您带领他们走向更辉煌的日子。他们的决心坚定，他们转向您，他们敬爱的铁血宰相，再次指引他们。您将通过铁与血来统治和征服，还是培育日耳曼艺术与工业？您能否建立一个经得起时间考验的文明？
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Civilopedia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_TITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>奥托·冯·俾斯麦</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_SUBTITLE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>德意志帝国宰相</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_QUOTE" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>没有武器的外交就像没有乐器的音乐。</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>奥托·冯·俾斯麦，劳恩堡公爵兼俾斯麦亲王，1815年4月1日出生于舍恩豪森，1898年7月30日在腓特烈斯鲁逝世，是一位普鲁士及后来的德意志政治家。他于1862年至1890年间同时担任普鲁士王国首相，1867年至1871年担任北德意志邦联首相，之后于1871年成为新生的德意志帝国的首任宰相，并任职至1890年，同时保留其普鲁士首相职位。他在德国统一进程中扮演了决定性角色。在其政治生涯初期，俾斯麦通过捍卫容克（普鲁士贵族，他本人也是其中一员）的利益，在保守派席位中崭露头角。他于1862年被任命为普鲁士首相。在普鲁士宪法冲突中，他为维护君主制的首要地位而与自由派斗争。同时兼任外交大臣的他，在1864年至1866年间发动了石勒苏益格-荷尔斯泰因战争和普奥战争，从而确立了普鲁士在德意志的霸权地位。1870年的普法战争通过采纳普鲁士支持的“小德意志方案”解决了德意志问题，并导致了1871年的德意志统一。此后，在外交政策上，他试图通过一套联盟体系在欧洲列强间建立平衡。</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>在国内政策方面，从1866年开始，俾斯麦首先与温和自由派结盟，这导致了许多改革的通过，例如设立民事婚姻，这遭到了天主教徒的抵抗，他通过推行“文化斗争”政策对他们进行了强烈反对。在1870年代末，他与自由派分道扬镳，重新与保守派合作。在此阶段，通过了保护主义和国家干预主义的法律。还创建了一套社会保障体系。1880年代主要以反社会主义法为标志。1890年，俾斯麦与新皇帝威廉二世意见相左，导致他去职。辞职后，俾斯麦继续扮演政治角色，批评其继任者的行动。他还撰写了回忆录，强烈影响了德国舆论对他的看法。直到20世纪中叶，德国历史学家大多从正面评价他的作为，在民族主义盛行的这一时期，他的作为与德国的统一联系在一起。然而，第二次世界大战后，批评之声渐起：他被指责作为德意志帝国的奠基人，应对德国民主的失败负责。不过，更现代的历史研究方法试图将俾斯麦的行动，连同其优点与缺点，置于其所处时代及当时存在的政治结构背景中来考量。</Text>
		</Row>



 
		
		
		
		
		<!--Diplomacy-->
		<!--FIRST MEET-->
		<!--First AI line-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>以伟大的德意志人民的名义，我欢迎您！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to visit nearby City-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>您好，我是奥托·冯·俾斯麦，德国宰相！您想参观我们最近的城市吗？</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI accepts Human invitation-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>谢谢。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to exchange Capital Information-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我邀请您交换我们各自首都的信息。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--GREETINGS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>问候！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DELEGATION-->
		<!--AI Accepts-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我很高兴接受您的代表团！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>不幸的是，不行。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我向您派遣一个商务代表团，并带上来自我国的礼物：香肠和啤酒，很多啤酒……</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--OPEN BORDERS-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>是的，我同意向您的小士兵们开放我的边界。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI rejects from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我们目前不感兴趣。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>您同意我们穿越您的领土吗？</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE FRIENDSHIP-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我同意向世界宣告我们的友谊。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects from human -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我拒绝向世界宣告我们的友谊。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests friendship from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>仔细考虑这个提议对您最有利。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human accepts AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>谢谢你。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human rejects AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>那太遗憾了。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ALLIANCE-->
		<!--AI Requests an alliance from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>您想结盟吗？</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--KUDOS & WARNINGS-->
		<!--AI Kudos-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>你很顽强！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Warnings-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>你是个软蛋！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI warns player for border troops-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>一伙令人作呕的士兵在我们边境附近集结……您想在不幸事件发生前把他们撤走吗？</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--TRADE-->
		<!--AI Accepts Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DENOUNCE-->
		<!--From Human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我公开谴责你！）Ich prangere dich öffentlich an!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--From AI-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>你们在背后搞阴谋。请放心，我会警告其他人！ (谴责您).</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE WAR-->
		<!--Human Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我不能等到你们变得更强大。因此，准备战争吧！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>腐败的恶棍！我们会把你们打入地下！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MAKE PEACE-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>让我们讲和吧！</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI refuses human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>当然不。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>我提议休战，您觉得什么时候合适？</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DEFEAT-->
		<!--AI is Defeated-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>德国已被摧毁。我为未来的世代哭泣。</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is Defeated (will see this in hotseat)-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY" Language="zh_Hans_CN">
			<Text>[LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_GEDEMO_BISMARK_ANY]</Text>
		</Row>

		

		
	</LocalizedText>
</GameData>
