<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- DiploText -->
<!-- Author: Richard -->
<!-- DateCreated: 12/3/2017 6:10:28 PM -->
<GameData>
	<LocalizedText>
		<!--DOM-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV" Language="en_US">
			<Text>You are Yaroslav I Vladimirovich, The Wise, Grand Prince of Kyiv, Prince of Novgorod and Rostov. Your focus on foreign policy and strengthened the bonds of alliance will do you well in the time to come. As many of your neighbors seek to covet your lands, look to those with whom you find a common foe, and make use of their strength alongside your own. With these bonds of alliance, you will fortify the borders of Kyivan Rus' and ensure your legacy remains until the end of time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Agenda-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_MER_OLD_LAW_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Old Law</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_MER_OLD_LAW_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Emphasizes War of Retribution, Liberation War, and Protectorate War and admires those who declare these types of war. Likes Civilizations that establish Alliances. Dislikes those who don't establish Alliances and declare Surprise Wars.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--KUDOS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDOS_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_REASON_ALLIANCES" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have many Alliances)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_OLD_LAW_ALLIANCES" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav is impressed by your many alliances.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDOS_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_REASON_RETRIBUTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have declared a War of Retribution)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_OLD_LAW_RETRIBUTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav admires your declaration of a War of Retribution.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDOS_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_REASON_LIBERATION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have declared a Liberation War)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_OLD_LAW_LIBERATION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav admires your declaration of a Liberation War.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDOS_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_REASON_PROTECTORATE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have declared a Protectorate War)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_OLD_LAW_PROTECTORATE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav admires your declaration of a Protectorate War.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--WARNING-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_REASON_LOW_ALLIANCES" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have few alliances)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_OLD_LAW_LOW_ALLIANCES" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav is unimpressed by your few alliances.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_REASON_SURPRISE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You declared a Surprise War)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_OLD_LAW_SURPRISE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav is angered by your Surprise War</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Civilopedia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_TITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_SUBTITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Grand Prince of Kyiv and Novgorod</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_QUOTE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Love each other because you are brethren from one father and mother. If you love one another, then God will be with you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav The Wise was thrice grand prince of Veliky Novgorod and Kyiv, uniting the two principalities for a time under his rule. A son of Vladimir the Great, the first Christian Prince of Novgorod, Yaroslav acted as vice-regent of Novgorod at the time of his father's death in 1015. Subsequently, his eldest surviving brother, Sviatopolk I of Kyiv, killed three of his other brothers and seized power in Kyiv. Yaroslav, with the active support of the Novgorodians and the help of Varangian mercenaries, defeated Svyatopolk and became the Grand Prince of Kyiv in 1019. Under Yaroslav the codification of legal customs and princely enactments was begun, and this work served as the basis for a law code called the Russkaya Pravda. During his lengthy reign, Kyivan Rus' reached the zenith of its cultural flowering and military power.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In his youth, Yaroslav was sent by his father to rule the northern lands around Rostov but was transferred to Veliky Novgorod, as befitted a senior heir to the throne, in 1010. While living there, he founded the town of Yaroslavl (literally, "Yaroslav's") on the Volga River. His relations with his father were apparently strained, and grew only worse on the news that Vladimir bequeathed the Kyivan throne to his younger son, Boris. In 1014 Yaroslav refused to pay tribute to Kyiv and only Vladimir's death, in July 1015, prevented a war. Leaving aside the legitimacy of Yaroslav's claims to the Kyivan throne and his postulated guilt in the murder of his brothers, Nestor the Chronicler and later Russian historians often presented him as a model of virtue, styling him "the Wise". A less appealing side of his personality is revealed by his having imprisoned his youngest brother Sudislav for life. Yet another brother, Mstislav of Chernigov, whose distant realm bordered the North Caucasus and the Black Sea, hastened to Kyiv and, despite reinforcements led by Yaroslav's brother-in-law King Anund Jacob of Sweden, inflicted a heavy defeat on Yaroslav in 1024. Yaroslav and Mstislav then divided Kyivan Rus' between them: the area stretching left from the Dnieper River, with the capital at Chernihiv, was ceded to Mstislav until his death in 1036.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>In his foreign policy, Yaroslav relied on the Scandinavian alliance and attempted to weaken the Byzantine influence on Kyiv. In 1030, he reconquered Red Ruthenia from the Poles and concluded an alliance with King Casimir I the Restorer, sealed by the latter's marriage to Yaroslav's sister, Maria. In another successful military raid the same year, he captured Tartu, Estonia and renamed it Yuryev (named after Yury, Yaroslav's patron saint) and forced the surrounding Ugandi County to pay annual tribute. In 1043, Yaroslav staged a naval raid against Constantinople led by his son Vladimir of Novgorod and general Vyshata. Although his navy was defeated in the Rus'–Byzantine War (1043), Yaroslav managed to conclude the war with a favourable treaty and prestigious marriage of his son Vsevolod I of Kyiv to the emperor's daughter. It has been suggested that the peace was so advantageous because the Kyivans had succeeded in taking a key Byzantine possession in Crimea, Chersonesus.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yaroslav relies on alliances and trade to strengthen Kyivan Rus.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Diplomacy-->
		<!--FIRST MEET-->
		<!--First AI line-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Welcome, I am Yaroslav. Should you be a wise and fair ruler, we will be fast friends and you need not fear my justice.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to visit nearby City-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Come, visit my nearby city! I am sure you will be pleased with the experience, and we'd love to have you!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI accepts Human invitation-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, yes, my friend! I would love to.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to exchange Capital Information-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I am sure your capital is filled with many people like me. It'd be great to meet them! Of course, where is your capital? Would you be willing to share that with me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--GREETINGS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes? What can I do for you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DELEGATION-->
		<!--AI Accepts-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, my friend! I am looking forward to meeting them and accepting their gifts!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I am sorry, but perhaps another time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>My friend, a delegation is on the way to your capital. I think you'll love to meet them!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--OPEN BORDERS-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, of course!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI rejects from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I would love to accept this offer, but I can't... I am deeply sorry, truly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Your borders are closed right now. Would you be open to opening them? Ha, ha, ha - do you see what I did there? No? </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE FRIENDSHIP-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, definitely! Now I can call you a friend and it is legally true too! I am more delighted than you would understand, trust me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Sorry, but sometimes it's best just to be friends in life and not in a formal way. It keeps things free, you know? Again, I am so sorry that I couldn't accept.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests friendship from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>You have been a great friend to me. Perhaps we could make our friendship official and formal?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human accepts AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, thank you! Just what I expected. I would reach out and shake your hand, but I have a bit of a cold and do not want you to get sick - even if I am wearing gloves. Anyway, thanks so much!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human rejects AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Well, that's not very kind, is it?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ALLIANCE-->
		<!--AI Requests an alliance from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>My friend, can you imagine how great an alliance would be? The world would be jealous of the greatness and prosperity our kingdoms would have. We could protect each other, but also attack anyone who stands in our way. And, how could I forget - we would almost be drowning in coin! Oh, the merriment! Will you be my ally, my friend?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--KUDOS & WARNINGS-->
		<!--AI Kudos-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>My friend, you are a great man and a great merchant. Good job!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Warnings-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I don't want to cause any trouble, but you aren't being a good ally, and you aren't using your money wisely. It is so very disappointing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI warns player for border troops-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>You know, you're making me quite nervous.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--TRADE-->
		<!--AI Accepts Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, yes, of course, my friend!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Rejects Deal -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Well, that's not very kind, is it?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DENOUNCE-->
		<!--From Human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I do not have to take such an insult.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--From AI-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I hate to do this to you, but... you have betrayed my trust too many times. I have my limits. You are hereby denounced. (Denounces You).</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Rationale-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_REASON_FROM_AI_LEADER_ANY_REASON_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_THE_WISE_NO_ALLIANCES" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have little to no alliances)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_REASON_FROM_AI_LEADER_ANY_REASON_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_THE_WISE_LOW_INCOME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have low income)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE WAR-->
		<!--Human Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>That is not very kind of you. I will let you know this - when you are crushed, I will treat your people well. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I hate to make an enemy or do anything like this, but you are like an annoying bee that tries to sting me. You vex and irritate me, and sometimes cause me harm. The only way to get rid of the bee is to kill it, so I hereby declare war on you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MAKE PEACE-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, my friend! I am glad to accept this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI refuses human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>No. Sorry. I cannot...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>My friend, let us lay down our weapons and take up our plows and quills. It is time to live normally again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DEFEAT-->
		<!--AI is Defeated-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Justice will be brought down upon you, just a pity that it will not be my arm that brings down the axe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is Defeated (will see this in hotseat)-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_MER_KYIV_YAROSLAV_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>It is a shame really.</Text>
		</Row>
	</LocalizedText>
</GameData>
